{
    "question": "1)  Name the oldest Grand Slam tennis tournament that has been \nscrapped for the first time since World War II due to havoc of \nCorona",
    "answer": "  Wimbledon, London \n"
}{
    "question": "2)  The Union cabinet has approved a _____ percent cut in the \nsalaries of the Members of Parliament for one year wef April 1 \nthis year",
    "answer": "  30% \n"
}{
    "question": "3)  The Union cabinet has decided to suspend MPLADS funds for \ntwo  years  from  2020-21  to  2022,   What  is  the  full  form  of \nMPLADS",
    "answer": "    Member  of  Parliament  Local  Area  Development \nScheme \n"
}{
    "question": "4)  Every  MP  gets  how  much  funds  every  year  under  the \nMPLADS",
    "answer": "  Rs 5 crore \n"
}{
    "question": "5)  The Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE) has decided \nto  introduce  three  new  subjects  for  class  11  from  2020-21 \nacademic  session  Name  these  subjects",
    "answer": "  Design  Thinking, \nPhysical Activity Trainer and Artificial Intelligence \n"
}{
    "question": "6)  Which  global  agency  has  approved  a  fast-track  $1  billion \nsupport  for  \u201cIndia  Covid  Emergency  Response  and  Health \nSystems Preparedness Project\u201d",
    "answer": "  The World Bank \n"
}{
    "question": "7)  The Great Barrier Reef, the world\u2019s largest coral reef system has \nsuffered its worst mass coral bleaching in recent years Where is \nit located",
    "answer": "  In the sea around northeast Australia \n"
}{
    "question": "8)  Name the FIFA event that was to be held in India in November \nthis  year,  which  has  been  postponed  by  FIFA  due  to  the \nworsening COVID-19 pandemic across the globe",
    "answer": "  The FIFA \nUnder-17 Women\u2019s World Cup \n"
}{
    "question": "9)  The New Delhi _________ World Cup, which had already been \npostponed from March to May, has now been cancelled due to \nthe Covid-19 pandemic",
    "answer": "  Shooting \n"
}{
    "question": "10)  The Central Government has approved a double-digit hike in \nthe wages of manual labourers under MNREGA The letter G \nstands for what",
    "answer": " Guarantee  \n"
}{
    "question": "11)  The World Health Day is celebrated around the globe on which \ndate",
    "answer": "  April 07 \n"
}{
    "question": "12)  What is the name of the main mobile app launched for tracking \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  124 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nand fighting COVID-19, launched by the Central Government",
    "answer": "  \n\u2018Aarogya Setu\u2019 \n"
}{
    "question": "13)  Name the British cricketer who co-invented the Duckworth-\nLewis Method, who died on April 1 at the age of 78",
    "answer": "   Tony Lewis \n"
}{
    "question": "15)  The World Homoeopathy Day is observed on which date",
    "answer": " April \n10 \n"
}{
    "question": "16)  Who is known as the father of the Homoeopathic system of \nmedicines",
    "answer": "   Dr Samuel Hahnemann  \n"
}{
    "question": "17)  India celebrates National Safe Motherhood Day on April 11 \nThis  day  also  commemorates  the  birth  day  of  which  great \nIndian lady social worker",
    "answer": "  Kasturba Gandhi \n"
}{
    "question": "18)  Which organisation supports the celebration of the  National \nSafe Motherhood Day",
    "answer": "  White Ribbon Alliance India \n"
}{
    "question": "19)  Indian football team retained its ______ spot in the latest FIFA \nrankings",
    "answer": "  108th \n"
}{
    "question": "20)  Which ministry launched Bharat Padhe Online campaign on \nApril 11 to crowdsource ideas for improving the online education \necosystem of India",
    "answer": "   The Union Ministry of Human Resources \nDevelopment \n"
}{
    "question": "21)  These days we hear a lot about providing PPEs to doctors and \nmedical staff What is full form of PPE",
    "answer": "  Personal Protection \nEquipment \n"
}{
    "question": "22)  Which funding agency has has assured $2o2 billion (about Rs \n16,500 crore) support to India in its fight against the Covid-19 \npandemic",
    "answer": "  The Asian Development Bank \n"
}{
    "question": "23)  Name  the  England\u2019s  all-rounder  who  has  been  named  the \nleading cricketer in the world  2020 by Wisden",
    "answer": "  Ben Stokes \n"
}{
    "question": "24)  Which national day is celebrated to commemorate the sailing of \nfirst Indian ship from Mumbai to London",
    "answer": "  National Maritime \nDay, April 5 \n"
}{
    "question": "25)  Which global day is observed on April 2 to highlight the need to \nimprove  the  quality  of  life  of  those  suffering  with  Autism",
    "answer": "  \nWorld Autism Awareness Day \n"
}{
    "question": "26)  The Indian Air Force conducted \u2018Operation Sanjeevani\u2019 to air-\nlift 6o2 tonnes of essential medical supplies to which country",
    "answer": "  \nMaldives \n"
}{
    "question": "27)  The Olympic Council of Asia unveiled the official mascots of the \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  125 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \n19th  Asian  Games-2022  Which  city  will  host  these  games",
    "answer": "  \nHangzhou, China \n"
}{
    "question": "29)  What is the single name given to the three mascots of 19th \nAsian Games-2022",
    "answer": "   The Smart Triplets \n"
}{
    "question": "30)  Who is the Chief of the Indian Air Force",
    "answer": "  Air Chief Marshal \nRakesh Kumar Singh Bhadauria \n"
}{
    "question": "31)  In which state Baisakhi is celebrated as Naba Barsha",
    "answer": "  West \nBengal \n"
}{
    "question": "32)  Vishu is a famous festival of which state",
    "answer": "  Kerala \n"
}{
    "question": "35)  What kind of weapon is a Torpedo",
    "answer": "  A guided missile usually \nfired from a submarine \n"
}{
    "question": "36)  M  S  Mahabaleshwara  has  been re-appointed  as  the MD  and \nCEO of which private sector",
    "answer": "  Karnataka Bank \n"
}{
    "question": "37)  World Art Day is celebrated with support from UNESCO on \nwhich day of April",
    "answer": "  15th \n"
}{
    "question": "38)  Which  country  has  decided  to  stop  funding  for  the  World \nHealth  Organization  (WHO),  accusing  it  of  grossly \nmismanaging  and  covering-up  the  spread  of  the  novel \ncoronavirus",
    "answer": "  USA \n"
}{
    "question": "39)  Reserve Bank of India on April 17 announced several regulatory \nmeasures aimed at boosting liquidity in the market It slashed \nwhich policy rate by 25 basis points",
    "answer": "  Reverse Repo Rate \n"
}{
    "question": "40)  RBI announced a booster package of 50,000 crore rupees for \nsupporting  which  sector  of  economy  to  recover  from  the \nlockdown",
    "answer": " Small and Medium-sized industries  \n"
}{
    "question": "41)  The RBI Governor declared that the period of resolution plan \nfor NPAs will be extended by ____ days",
    "answer": "  90 \n"
}{
    "question": "42)  An Integrated Geospatial Platform named _________has been \nrolled out by the Deptt of Science and Technology, Govt of \nIndia, to help in decision making during the present COVID-19 \noutbreak",
    "answer": "   SAHYOG \n"
}{
    "question": "43)  The WWF (World Wide Fund) India has appointed veteran \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  126 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nworld chess champion ___________ as its ambassador for the \nenvironmental education program",
    "answer": "  Viswanathan Anand \n"
}{
    "question": "44)  World Hemophilia Day is observed on April 17 across the world \nHemophilia is related to which ailment",
    "answer": " Bleeding disorders \n"
}{
    "question": "45)  Fei Fei the bird has been unveiled as the mascot for which Asian \nPara Games",
    "answer": "  Hangzhou (China) 2022 Asian Para Games \n"
}{
    "question": "46)  World Heritage Day is observed on which date",
    "answer": "  April 18  \n"
}{
    "question": "47)  What  is  the  name  of  the  mobile  app  launched  to  facilitate \ntransportation  of  food  grains  and  perishables  like  fruits  and \nvegetables, during lockdown",
    "answer": "  Kissan Rath \n"
}{
    "question": "48)  Which Indian two wheeler company has acquired the United \nKingdom\u2019s  most  iconic  sporting  motorcycle  brand  \u2018Norton\u2019",
    "answer": "  \nTVS Motors \n"
}{
    "question": "49)  Name the world's most famous cycling race, held every year in \nFrance,  which  has  been  postponed  in  the  wake  of  the \nCoronavirus pandemic",
    "answer": "  Tour de France \n"
}{
    "question": "50)  April 19 is celebrated around the world to promote awareness \nabout one of the most complex organ in the body Can you name \nit",
    "answer": "  Liver \n"
}{
    "question": "51)  Which great Indian statesman termed civil servants as the \u2018steel \nframe of India\u2019",
    "answer": "  Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel \n"
}{
    "question": "52)  Which  International  day  is  observed  on  April  22  to  create \nawareness about pollution and to celebrate the environment of \nour planet",
    "answer": "  The Earth Day \n"
}{
    "question": "53)  Social media and tech giant Facebook invested Rs 43,574 crore \nfor securing a 9o99 per cent stake in which Indian company",
    "answer": "   \nJio Platforms \n"
}{
    "question": "54)  ______________ became the first state on April 19 to geo-tag \ncommunity kitchens being run in the state",
    "answer": "  Uttar Pradesh \n"
}{
    "question": "55)  Name the creator of most popular animation characters Tom \nand Jerry, Popeye the Sailor, who passed away at the age of 95 \nat his residence in Prague, Czechoslovakia",
    "answer": "  Gene Deitch \n"
}{
    "question": "56)  Kapil Dev Tripathi has been appointed as the new Secretary to \nwhich apex authority",
    "answer": "  President of India \n"
}{
    "question": "57)  Which  bank  has  rolled  out  a  new  feature  of  voice  banking \nservices  on  Amazon  Alexa  and  Google  Assistant  for  its \ncustomers",
    "answer": "  ICICI Bank \n"
}{
    "question": "58)  HRD  Ministry  launched  the  national  program  named \n_________ for inviting e-learning content contributions for both \nschool and higher education",
    "answer": "  VidyaDaan 2o0 \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  127 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \n"
}{
    "question": "59)  April 23 is observed globally every year as English Language \nDay to mark the birthday and date of death of which legendary \nwriter",
    "answer": "   William Shakespeare \n"
}{
    "question": "60)  The  UNESCO  has  selected  which  city  as  the  World  Book \nCapital for 2020",
    "answer": "  Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia \n"
}{
    "question": "61)  National  Panchayati  Raj  Day  is  celebrated  on  which  date",
    "answer": "  \nApril 24 \n"
}{
    "question": "62)  Which  amendment  of  Indian  Constitution  introduced  the \nPanchayati Raj Act in 1993",
    "answer": "  73rd amendment \n"
}{
    "question": "63)  The Prime Minister launched which two major schemes for rural \nareas on April 24",
    "answer": " e-Gram Swaraj Portal and Swamitva \n"
}{
    "question": "64)  The World Bank has approved $82 million for the State Roads \nTransformation Project of which state for upgradation of major \nroads and modernization of the Public Works Department in the \nstate",
    "answer": "  Himachal Pradesh \n"
}{
    "question": "65)  Name the eminent theatre personality who died at her residence \nin south Kolkata on April 23, at the age of 75",
    "answer": "  Usha Ganguly \n"
}{
    "question": "66)  The Global Press Freedom Index has ranked India at which \nspot",
    "answer": "  142nd \n"
}{
    "question": "67)  Which country topped the the Global Press Freedom Index",
    "answer": "  \nNorway \n"
}{
    "question": "68)  Which institution has claimed to have developed a potential \nCOVID-19 vaccine, the first human trials of which began on \nApril 23, 2020",
    "answer": "  Oxford University, London \n"
}{
    "question": "69)  Who  has  been  appointed  as  the  new  Chief  Vigilance \nCommissioner of India",
    "answer": "    Sanjay Kothari \n"
}{
    "question": "70)  Which  international  day  is  celebrated  on  April  25  to  raise \nawareness about a globally present disease",
    "answer": "  World Malaria Day \n"
}{
    "question": "71)  Malaria is a life-threatening disease which is caused by ________ \nParasites",
    "answer": "  Plasmodium \n"
}{
    "question": "72)  The Plasmodium parasite is spread by which insect",
    "answer": " Female \nAnopheles mosquitoes \n"
}{
    "question": "73)  What is the theme for this year\u2019s World Malaria Day",
    "answer": "  Zero \nmalaria starts with me \n"
}{
    "question": "74)  Government has declared banking industry as a public utility \nservice for six months till October 21 under the provisions of \nwhich Act",
    "answer": " Industrial Disputes Act, 1947 \n"
}{
    "question": "75)  __________ has become the first state to have the requisite \ninfrastructure in all its courts for hearing cases through video \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  128 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nconferencing",
    "answer": "  Uttar Pradesh \n"
}{
    "question": "76)  Which  country  successfully  launched  its  first-ever  military \nsatellite named \u201cNoor\u201d into orbit",
    "answer": "  Iran \n"
}{
    "question": "77)  According  to  a  Swedish  research  institute,  Stockholm \nInternational Peace Research Institute (SIPRI), India is the \n____ biggest spender on military hardware",
    "answer": "  Third \n"
}{
    "question": "78)  As per SIPRI report, ___________ is the biggest spender of \nmilitary expenditure",
    "answer": "  USA \n"
}{
    "question": "79)  Which country has declared an end to the death penalty for \ncrimes committed by minors",
    "answer": "  Saudi Arabia \n"
}{
    "question": "80)  The Reserve Bank announced on April 27 a Special Liquidity \nFacility of Rs 50,000 crore for which sector of economy",
    "answer": "  Mutual \nfunds \n"
}{
    "question": "81)  World Day for Safety and Health at Work is observed on which \nday",
    "answer": "  April 28 \n"
}{
    "question": "82)  Which UN agency supports the celebrations of the World Day \nfor  Safety  and  Health  at  Work",
    "answer": "    International  Labour \nOrganization (ILO) \n"
}{
    "question": "83)  The  BRICS  Ministers  of  Foreign  Affairs  summit  was  held \nthrough a video conference on April 28, 2020  It was hosted by \nwhich country",
    "answer": "  Russia \n"
}{
    "question": "84)  What is the full form of the UN special agency WIPO",
    "answer": "  World \nIntellectual Property Office, Geneva \n"
}{
    "question": "85)  What is the theme of this year\u2019s World Intellectual Property \nDay",
    "answer": "  Innovate for a Green Future \n"
}{
    "question": "86)  Who has been appointed as the next Ambassador / Permanent \nRepresentative of India to the United Nations",
    "answer": "  T S Tirumurti \n"
}{
    "question": "87)  The International Dance Day is celebrated on which day of \nApril",
    "answer": "  29th \n"
}{
    "question": "88)  The  11th  session  of  Petersburg  Climate  Dialogue  with  30 \ncountries  including  India  was  hosted  by  which  country",
    "answer": "  \nGermany \n"
}{
    "question": "89)  Who represented India at the 11th session of Petersburg Climate \nDialogue",
    "answer": "    Prakash  Javadekar,  the  Union  Minister  for \nEnvironment, Forest and Climate Change \n"
}{
    "question": "90)  Name the veteran Bollywood actor who passed away on Apri \n30, losing his battle against Leukemia",
    "answer": "  Rishi Kapoor  "
}